Guide to the Nell Irvin Painter Papers, 1793-2021 and undated, bulk 1876-2007 RL.00990
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings and Research Series, 1793, 1835-2007 and undated, bulk 1876-2004, 66 boxes
  - Other Research Topics Subseries, 1793, 1847-2007 and undated, bulk 1975-2002, 22 boxes
    - Southern History
      - Fraser, Walter J., Jr., and Winfred B. Moore, Jr.: From the Old South to the New, 1981 (Box 140)
      - Gayarre: The Southern Question, 1877 (Box 140)
      - Philips, James J., Papers, Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1865-1866; notes, undated (Box 141)
      - Ku Klux Klan, Greensboro, 1979 (Box 141)
      - Ku Klux Klan investigations, 1871-1872, 2 folders (Box 141)
      - Lenoir Family Papers, Southern Historical Collections, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1865-1866; notes undated; photocopies, 1865-1866 (Box 141)
      - Litwack Review, (NIP), The Nation, 1998 (Box 141)
      - Lumpkin, Katherine, 1982 (Box 141)
      - MacKay-Stiles Family Papers, Southern Historical Collections, University of North Carolina, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1865; notes, undated (Box 141)
      - Madden, T. O., manuscript, circa 1991, 2 folders (Box 141)
      - My review of J. Cobb, Southern Place on Earth, 1993 (Box 141)
      - New York Times, 1887; notes, undated (Box 141)
      - New York Times book review of J. C. Cobb's The Most Southern Place..., (NIP), 1992 (Box 141)
      - New York Tribune, 1887-1899 (Box 141)
      - An Overview of Southern History, (NIP), 1984 Oct. (Box 141)
      - Page, Thomas Nelson: The Old South, 1892 (Box 141)
      - Page, Walter Hines: The Southerner, 1909 (Box 141)
      - Pure Blood and Mixed Blood..., (NIP), Rutgers University, 1983 Jan. 20 (Box 141)
      - Quitman Family Papers, Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1865; notes, undated (Box 141)
      - Recent dissertations, circa 1983 (Box 141)
      - Reconstruction
        - Benedict, Michael Les: Southern Democrats in the Crisis of 1876-1877..., 1980 (Box 141)
        - Bibliography, 1986; research materials, 1961-1984 (Box 141)
        - Bibliography, 1987 (Box 141)
        - Bibliography, circa 1987 (Box 141)
        - Brock, Euline W.: Thomas W. Cardozo: Fallible Black Reconstruction Leader, 1981 (Box 141)
        - Donald, David H.: Scalawag in Mississippi: Reconstruction, 1944 (Box 141)
        - Hine: William C.: Black Politicians in Reconstruction Charleston..., 1983 (Box 141)
        - Hosmer, John and Joseph Fineman: Black Congressman in Reconstruction, 1978 (Box 142)
        - Humphrey, George D.: Failure of the Mississippi Freedmen's Bureau..., 1983 (Box 142)
        - Kolchin, Peter: Scalawags, Carpetbaggers, and Reconstruction..., 1979 (Box 142)
        - Matthews, John M.: Jefferson Franklin Long: The Public Career of Georgia's First Black Congressman, 1981 (Box 142)
        - Moor, James Tice: Redeemers Reconsidered: Change and Continuity in the Democratic South, 1870-1900, 1978 (Box 142)
        - Silverman, Catherine: Trends in Black Reconstruction History, 1982 (Box 142)
        - The South, 1865-1866, primary sources from Southern Historical Collection UNC-CH (Box 142)
      - Review of E. Ayers, (NIP), 1992 (Box 142)
      - Review of Foner, Reconstruction: America's Unfinished Revolution, 1863-1877, (NIP), Boston Globe, 1988 (Box 142)
      - Review of Woodson Goggins' Southern Cultures, (NIP), 1994 (Box 142)
      - Robert Philip Howell Memoirs, Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, notes, undated (Box 142)
      - Roy Patishau, Chapel Hill, 1917 and 1989 (Box 142)
      - Second Baptist Church of Frankford, Philadelphia, 1969; History of the American South, (NIP), 1988 (Box 142)
      - "Shoah and Southern History," draft and research 1998 (Box 262)
      - Shoah and Southern History, (NIP), 2002 Oct. 11 (Box 142)
      - The 'South' and 'The Negro,' (NIP), The South for Non-Southerners, 1987, 2 folders (Box 142)
      - Southern Discomfort...One Family's Story, (NIP), 1984 Sept. (Box 142)
      - Southern History Across the Color Line, book cover sample, undated (Box 262)
      - Southern History Across the Color Line, (NIP), 2000 (Box 142)
      - The South in 1865, (NIP), American Studies Faculty, Chapel Hill, 1987 Apr. 7 (Box 142)
      - The South in 1865, (NIP), Johns Hopkins University (LO), 1987 May 1 (Box 142)
      - The South in 1865, (NIP), Johns Hopkins University (SH), 1987 May 3 (Box 142)
      - The South in the 1950s, material, undated (Box 142)
      - Table of Contents, American Views of the South, (NIP), 1986 Dec. (Box 142)
      - Trelease, Allen W., Who Were the Scalawags? Journal of Southern History, 1963 Nov. (Box 142)
      - United States South in 1865:...Anger, Land and Wages..., (NIP), 1988, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box 142)
      - United States South in 1865:...Anger, Land and Wages..., (NIP), 1988, Folder 3 of 3 (Box 262)
      - Washington Post Book World Review, (NIP), 1996; Favorite books, (NIP), 1995 (Box 142)
      - William Gaston Lewis Papers, Southern Historical Collection, University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill, 1865; notes, undated (Box 142)
      - Who Speaks for the South? (NIP), Southern Exposure, 1984 (Box 142)
      - The World Turned Upside Down: The South in 1865, (NIP): addresses, drafts, and research notes, 19 folders
        - Cauthen, Charles E., Family Letters of the Three Wade Hamptons, 1953 (Box 142)
        - Clark, E. Culpepper, Francis W. Dawson 1980 (Box 142)
        - Christian Recorder, research notes, undated (Box 142)
        - Duke University Library, research notes undated (Box 142)
        - Gibbon, John, Personal Recollections of the Civil War, 1978 (Box 142)
        - Gutman, Myron, War and Rural Life, 1980 (Box 142)
        - Josiah Gorgas Journal, Southern History Collection, UNC-CH (Box 142)
        - Manigault Family Papers, Southern History Collection, UNC-CH (Box 142)
        - Martin Delany and Wade Hampton III, and the end of Reconstruction, (NIP), Yale, 1986 Feb. (Box 142)
        - Papers of Thomas Ruffin, vols. 3 and 4, 1865 (Box 142)
        - Report of the Joint Commission on Reconstruction, 1st session, 29th Congress 1866 (Box 143)
        - Samuel A. Agnew Diary, Southern Historical Collection, UNC-CH, undated (Box 143)
        - South Carolina Department of Archives and History: Research notes on various collections (Box 143)
        - Southern Historical Collection, UNC-CH: research notes on various collections (Box 143)
        - Stearns, Carol and Peter, Anger, 1986 (Box 143)
        - The South in 1865: World Turned Upside Down, (NIP), 1987 (Box 143)
        - The World Turned Upside Down: The South in 1865, Johns Hopkins University, 1987, 2 folders (Box 143)
    - Walter White
      Materials compiled by Painter while working in the late 1980s with one of her students, Leah Hagedorn, on a reprint edition (never published) of the novels of Walter White, an early 20th century African American author and chief executive of the NAACP from 1929-1935. Subgroup contains copies of correspondence to, from, and about White; copies of his newspapers columns, fiction manuscripts, and other writings; and Painter's original correspondence, drafts, and notes about White's life and work. Arranged alphabetically based on Painter's original folder titles; descriptive words such as "correspondence" and "photocopies" were added as needed to clarify folder contents.
      - Al Smith Campaign, 1928 (Box 143)
      - Alternate endings to Fire in the Flint, photocopied manuscript pages, undated (Box 143)
      - Blackjack, photocopied manuscript pages and NIP commentary, undated (Box 143)
      - Carl White letter, 1961 (Box 143)
      - Carl White/Gladys White/Jane White, 1945 and 1960-1964 (Box 143)
      - Carter Woodson letter, 1924 (Box 143)
      - Color Line, (WFW), Temple Israel, 1951 (Box 143)
      - Columns, (WFW), 1942-1949, 4 folders (Box 143)
      - Correspondence, NIP with Leah Hagedorn and others, 1987-1989, 3 folders (Box 143)
      - Dictionary of American Negro Biography, Walter White (Box 143)
      - Dubois Institute Mulatto Symposium, 1986 (Box 143)
      - Eulogies, 1955 (Box 143)
      - Fame, (WFW), circa 1930s? (Box 143)
      - Fire in the Flint, photocopy of Knopf printing, 1924 (Box 143)
      - George White/Madeline White correspondence, 1929-1932 and 1949 (Box 143)
      - Hagedorn, Leah: A Brief Biography of Walter White, 1989 Apr. (Box 144)
      - How Much Democracy can the Negro Expect? (WFW), Commencement Address, Fisk University, 1941 (Box 144)
      - In France, WFW correspondence, 1927-1928 (Box 144)
      - Interview with Franklin Williams, NYC, 1988 Apr. 27 (Box 144)
      - Interview with Gloster Current, NYC, 1988 Apr. 27 (Box 144)
      - Interview with Marvel Cooke, NYC, 1988 Apr. 15 (Box 144)
      - Jane White, 1968 (Box 144)
      - Jewish Examiner, Blond Negro, 1948 (Box 144)
      - Joel Spingarn to Amy Spingarn Re: Walter White, 1926 Nov. 22 (Box 144)
      - Letters to and from WFW re: Fire in the Flint, reproductions from the Library of Congress Manuscripts Division, 1922-1925, 2 folders (Box 144)
      - Literary Administrators, undated (Box 144)
      - Literary matters post- Flight, 1933 (Box 144)
      - Louis T. Wright, 1950 (Box 144)
      - NAACP Address, (WFW), 1951 (Box 144)
      - NAACP Correspondence with James Weldon Johnson, 1929-1934 (Box 144)
      - NAACP Resignation Withdrawn, 1949 (Box 144)
      - Notes on Passing and Flight, 1929 and undated (Box 144)
      - On Race and Region, (NIP), Lincoln University, 1988 Mar. (Box 144)
      - On Race and Region, (NIP), St. Augustine College, 1988 Apr. (Box 144)
      - Passing, magazine articles, 1919 and 1932-1934 (Box 144)
      - Passing: A Past Phenomenon? (NIP), UNC-W, 1988 Mar. 29 (Box 144)
      - South, Dr. James: For White Only, circa 1959 (Box 144)
      - Survey Graphic, Harlem: Mecca of the New Negro, 1925 Mar. (Box 144)
      - Re: Poppy Cannon, 1933-1936 (Box 144)
      - Walter White Reprints, 1987-1989 (Box 144)
      - White, 1992 Jan. 8 (Box 144)
      - Zangrando, Robert, footnotes for his paper on Walter F. White, AHA Annual Meeting, 1985 (Box 144)
  - Writings by Others Subseries, 1859-2007 and undated, bulk 1972-1996, 11 boxes
    Consists of drafts, published works, and lectures by family members, colleagues, and other individuals. Although Painter probably used these materials for her own research, they have been placed in the Writings by Others Subseries because they were unrelated to, or could not be particularly identified with, any of her major books. Moreover, they have not been included among the materials in the Other Research Topics Subseries, although they frequently include notes or marginalia by Painter, because Painter organized these materials in such a way that the work in each folder is primarily the work of a single author other than herself. Correspondence, including notes from those sending materials to Painter, can be found in some folders, and related material from some authors may also be found in the Correspondence Series.
    Significant topics covered in the subseries include feminism, photography, and the history of photography. Other materials on photography are found in the Sojourner Truth Subseries and the Photography subgroup of the Other Research Topics Subseries. Of interest is a work by Painter's mother, Dona Irvin, about the members of Downs Memorial United Methodist Church. The work focuses on the lives of middle-class African-Americans rather than prominent figures or the underprivileged. Here entitled The Downs People, it was published as The Unsung Heart of Black America: A Middle-class Church at Midcentury.
    Materials in the Writings by Others Subseries are arranged alphabetically by surname.
    - Abu-Lughod, Lila: The Woman Question in Egypt: Notes on a Dynamic of Postcolonial Cultural Politics, 1994 (Box 144)
    - Alexander-Minter, Rae: undated, 2 writings (Box 144)
    - Andrews, Doris: Popular Religion and the Revolution, 1988 (Box 144)
    - Andrews, William L.: The Changing Rhetoric of the Nineteenth-Century Slave Narrative of the United States, 1989 (Box 144)
    - Baker, Houston A.: Of Fossils, Families, and Discourse, 1982 (Box 145)
    - Baker, Houston A.: Is There Anybody There? 1976 (Box 145)
    - Ball, Charles: Fifty Years in Chains.. ., 1859 (Box 145)
    - Balmer, Randall: Apocalypticism in America.. ., 1988 (Box 145)
    - Barash, Carol: The Character of Difference: The Creole Woman as Cultural Mediator in Narratives about Jamaica, 1990 (Box 145)
    - Berger, John X. and Olivier Richon: Other than Itself: Writing Photography, 1989 (Box 145)
    - Bergner, Gwen and Bayle Wald: Psychoanalysis and Race, circa 1990 (Box 145)
    - Berlin, Ira, Steven F. Miller, and Leslie S. Rowland: Afro-American Families in the Transition from Slavery to Freedom, 1988 (Box 145)
    - Bolton, Richard: Contest of Meaning, 1989 (Box 145)
    - Boris, Eileen: The Power of Motherhood: Black and White Activist Women Redefine the 'Political,' 1989 (Box 145)
    - Boyorin, Jonathan: Reading Exodus Into History, 1990 (Box 145)
    - Braverman, Harry: Labor and Monopoly Capital, 1974 (Box 145)
    - Breen, T.H.: 1990 and undated, 2 writings (Box 145)
    - Bridges, Amy: Rethinking Origins of Machine Politics, 1986 (Box 145)
    - Brody, David: Unidentified work, Chapters 17-21 and Painter's (?) review (draft), 1982 and undated, 2 folders (Box 145)
    - Broeck, Sabine: Gender Trouble in the Deep South: Women; Race and Slavery, 2006 (Box 261)
    - Brotz, Negro Social and Political Thought, 1850-1920, undated (Box 145)
    - Brown, Elsa B.: What Has Happened Here? 1992 (Box 145)
    - Butler, Anne M.: Still in Chains: Black Women in Western Prisons, 1865-1910, 1989 (Box 145)
    - Bynum, Victoria: Outside the Law.. ., 1995 (Box 145)
    - Carby, Hazel V.: 1990, 2003, undated, 3 writings (Box 145)
    - Cashin, Joan: Varina Howell Davis, 1990 (Box 145)
    - Cavell, Stanley: from The Claim of Reason, undated (Box 145)
    - Chase, Allan: False Correlations=Real Deaths: The Great Pellagra Cover-Up.. ., from Genetic Destiny, 1976 (Box 145)
    - Chase-Riboud, Barbara
      - Information on Dreamworks and Amistad suits, 1997-2000, 3 Folders (Box 145)
      - The Monument Drawing, exhibition catalog, 1998 (Box 145)
      - Four books by Chase-Riboud, 1979-1994 (Box 146)
    - Chirenje, J. Mutero: The Afro-American Factor in Southern African Ethiopianism, circa 1976 (Box 146)
    - Christian, Barbara: The Race for Theory, 1987 (Box 146)
    - Clinton, Catherine: "Southern Dishonor": Flesh, Blood, Race, and Bondage, 1991 (Box 146)
    - Colloquium: Ethnicity and Power in Colonial Encounters (Gruzinski, Kaplan and Kelly, Rafael, Segal, and Williamson), 1991, 2 Folders (Box 146)
    - Daniel, Pete: The Metamorphosis of Slavery, 1865-1900, 1979 (Box 146)
    - Daniels, Lee: before 1990, 2 writings (Box 146)
    - Darrah, William C.: Cartes de Visite in Nineteenth Century Photography, 1981 (Box 146)
    - Daval, Jean-Luc: Photography: History of an Art, 1982 (Box 147)
    - Davenport, Alma: The History of Photography, 1991 (Box 147)
    - Davidoff, Leonore: Beyond the Public and Private: Thought on Feminist History in the 1990s, 1992 (Box 147)
    - Davis, Thadious: Expanding the Limits, 1987 (Box 147)
    - Dawley, Alan: Southern Paternalism and the Race Question, undated (Box 147)
    - Dayan, Joan, 1991 and undated, 3 writings (Box 147)
    - Demeestere, Jeanette: "Velma de Montparnasse," Black Renaissance, undated (Box 262)
    - box 147 (Box 147)
    - Derthick, Martha: The National Guard in Politics, 1965 (Box 147)
    - Deutsch, Sarah: Gendering of Chicano History, 1991 (Box 147)
    - Didion, Joan: New York: Sentimental Journeys, 1991 (Box 147)
    - Diner, Hasia: The Accidental Irish: Jewish Migration to an Unlikely Place, 2003 (Box 147)
    - Dombrowski, Nicole: The 'Irrationality of Women' Bravery, undated (Box 147)
    - Douglas, Mary and Baron Isherwood: The World of Goods, notes, undated (Box 147)
    - DuBois, Ellen: 1975 and 1986, 2 writings (Box 147)
    - Dubnoff, Steven: A Method for Estimating the Economic Welfare of American Families of Any Composition: 1860-1909, 1980 (Box 147)
    - Durrill, Wayne K: Producing Poverty: Local Government and Economic Development in a New South County, 1874-1884, 1985 (Box 147)
    - Edgar, Bob: Bunche in South Africa, 1991 (Box 147)
    - Einaudi, Luca: Policies and Politics of Immigration Flows in Italy and France in the Twentieth Century, 2003 (Box 147)
    - Einbinder, Susan: God's Forgotten Sheep: Jewish Poetry and the Expulsion from France (1306), 2003 (Box 147)
    - Eisenstein, Sarah: Give Us Bread but Give Us Roses, 1983 (Box 147)
    - Ette, Ottmar: "'...que uno lamenta, como ha dejado de ser aleman': Alexander von Humbolt, Prusia y America," Literatura- Historia- Politica, 2004 (Box 262)
    - unspecified (Box 147)
    - Evans, William: From the Land of Canaan to the Land of Guinea, 1980 (Box 147)
    - Faust, Drew: 'Trying to Do a Man's Business': A Texas Woman as Slave Manager During the Civil War, 1991 (Box 147)
    - Fineman, Martha: Feminist Theory in Law, 1992 (Box 147)
    - Foster, George: "What is Folk Culture?" 1953 (Box 262)
    - Franklin, John Hope: North Carolina Conundrum, 2005 (Box 262)
    - Freund, Gisele: Photography and Society, 1980 (Box 147)
    - Gallop, Jane: Keys to Dora, 1982 (Box 147)
    - Garcia, Mario: The Life and Narrative of Bert Corona, 1993 (Box 147)
    - Gates, Henry Louis, Jr.: The Trope of a New Negro and the Reconstruction of the Image of the Black, 1988 (Box 147)
    - Giddings, Paula: The New Historians..., 1879 (Box 147)
    - Gilmore, Glenda: 1991-1992 and undated, 6 writings; 2 folders (Box 148)
    - Gladney, Rose: 'How Am I Going to Be Heard?': Selected Letters from Lillian Smith, undated (Box 148)
    - Gomez, Jewelle: Mountain High, 1988 (Box 148)
    - Greenough, Sarah, et al: On the Art of Fixing a Shadow.. ., 1989 (Box 148)
    - Greven, Philip: "The Self Shaped and Misshaped: The Protestant Temperament Reconsidered," 1994 (Box 262)
    - unspecified (Box 148)
    - Griffin, Susan: Pornography and Silence, 1981 (Box 148)
    - Gutierrez, David G.: The Carrot and the Cudgel: Reflections on the Contradictions of Citizenship in the Early Twentieth Century, 2003 (Box 148)
    - Gyory, Andrew: Yan-kee vs. Yan-ki: American Workers React to Chinese Laborers in 1870, 1986 (Box 148)
    - Hagedorn, Leah: Lost Cause and Southern Jews, 1993 (Box 148)
    - Hall, Stuart, 1977-1989, 14 writings (Box 148)
    - Hamilton, Kenneth: Townsite Speculation and the Origin of Boley, Oklahoma, 1976 (Box 148)
    - Hamilton, Tullia: Origins of the Club Movement Among Black Women, 1976 (Box 148)
    - Harris, Robert L.: Afro-American Historiography: Theory and Interpretation, undated (Box 148)
    - Haskins, Jim: The Statue of Liberty: An All-American Vision, 1986 (Box 148)
    - Hay, John: The Bread-Winners, 1884 (Box 148)
    - Hewitt, Nancy A. and Suzanne Lebsock: Visible Women, 1993 (Box 148)
    - Higginbotham, A. Leon: An Open Letter to Justice Clarence Thomas from a Federal Judicial Colleague, 1991 (Box 148)
    - Higginbotham, Don: George Washington and George Marshall: Some Reflections on the American Military Tradition, 1984 (Box 148)
    - Higginbotham, Evelyn: African-American Women's History and the Metalanguage of Race, undated (Box 148)
    - Hine, Darlene Clark: Afrocentrism, 1991 (Box 148)
    - Hollie: 1976, 2 writings (Box 148)
    - Holmes, Oliver Wendell: On photography, 1861 and 1864, 2 writings (Box 148)
    - Humez, Jean M.: Tubman via Bradford, 1991 (Box 149)
    - Hunt, Michael Doc: He's a Tall and Heavy Mother Ain't He? And Other Love Stories, 1977 (Box 149)
    - Huntley, Horace: The Red-Scare and Black Workers in Alabama: The International Union of Mine Mill and Smelter Workers, undated (Box 149)
    - Hurst, James Willard, Snakes in Ireland: A Conversation with Willard Hurst, Law and History Review, 1994 (Box 149)
    - Hyman, Michael: Taxation, Public Policy, and Political Dissent, undated (Box 149)
    - Irons, Martin: My Experiences in the Labor Movement, Lippincotts, 1886 (Box 149)
    - Irvin, Dona: The Downs People, undated, 2 folders (Box 149)
    - Jackson, Martin: Martin: A Fallen Hero, and various pamphlets, undated (Box 149)
    - Jefferson, Margo: Seducified by a Minstrel Show, New York Times, May 22, 1994 (Box 149)
    - Jeffrey, Richard and Michael Hendrickson: XIV-Probabilizing Pathology, The Aristotelian Society, 1988 (Box 149)
    - Johnson, Walter: An American Amistad: The Slave Trade, the Creole Revolt, and the History of the Black American, undated (Box 149)
    - Johnston, Jill: Primum Scribere, Deinde Vivere, Women Writing Women's Lives, 1995 (Box 149)
    - Jones, Rhett S.: before 1985, 2 writings (Box 149)
    - Jordan, June: The Rainbow Next Time, 1988 (Box 149)
    - Karcher, L. Carolyn: "The White 'Bystander' and the Black Journalist 'Abroad': Albion W. Tourgee and Ida B. Wells as Allies Against Lynching," Prospect, undated (Box 262)
    - --: "Ida B. Wells and Her Allies Against Lynching: A Transnational Perspective," Comparative American Studies, 2005 (Box 262)
    - box 149 (Box 149)
    - Kazin, Alfred: America Writing Now, 1980; On Native Ground, 1942 (Box 149)
    - Kelley, Mary: Negotiating a Self: Autobiography of M. Sedgwick, undated (Box 149)
    - Kempe, C. Henry, et al: The Battered-Child Syndrome, 1962 (Box 149)
    - Kerber, Linda: Diversity and the Transformation of American Studies, 1988 (Box 149)
    - Kerber, Linda K.: Separate Spheres, Female Worlds, Woman's Place, 1988; 'History Will Do It No Justice': Women's Lives in Revolutionary America, undated (Box 149)
    - Kilson, Martin: 1983 and undated, 3 writings (Box 149)
    - Koppelman, Andrew: Discrimination against Lesbians and Gays, 1994 (Box 149)
    - Kousser, Morgan: 2000, 2002, 2 writings (Box 149)
    - Lacoue-Labarthe, Philippe: poems, undated (Box 262)
    - unspecified (Box 149)
    - Lamuniere, Michelle C.: Roll, Jordan, Roll and the Gullah Photographs of Doris Ulmann, 1997 (Box 149)
    - Lawrence, Charles: 1987, 1989, undated, 4 writings (Box 149)
    - Lemagny, Jean-Claude and Andre Rouille: A History of Photography, 1987 (Box 149)
    - Lerner, Gerda: Rethinking Race; Rethinking Class, 1996 (Box 149)
    - Levin, David: Enlightenment, undated (Box 150)
    - Libow, Judith: Family secrets, 1985 (Box 150)
    - Linden, Diana L. and Larry A. Greene: "Charles Alston's Harlem Hospital Murals: Cultural Politics in Depression Era Harlem," Prospects, undated (Box 262)
    - box 150 (Box 150)
    - L'invention d'un regard, 1989 (Box 150)
    - Lucious, Bernard Scott: In the Black Pacific: Testimonies of Vietnamese Afro-Amerasian Displacements, undated (Box 150)
    - Marshall, Paule: From the Poets in the Kitchen, 1983 (Box 150)
    - Martin, Charles H.: Race, Gender, and Social Injustice: The Rosa Lee Ingram Case, undated (Box 150)
    - Martin, N.B. (Tad): Their Future Did Not Work--Will Ours? American Democracy in the Wake of the Cold War, circa 1995 (Box 150)
    - Mathews, Jane de Hart: The New Feminism and the Dynamics of Social Change, 1982 (Box 150)
    - Mayer, Arno: To Exorcise the Settlement Complex, 1994 (Box 150)
    - McBride, Dwight: It's All About Appropriation, undated (Box 150)
    - McCauley, Elizabeth Anne: The Rise and Fall of the Carte de Visite, 1986 (Box 150)
    - McGill, L. Alexis: Towards a Theory of Urban Secession Movements, 1998 (Box 150)
    - McKay, Nellie: on the Wheatley Court, PMLA, 1998 (Box 150)
    - McLaughlin, William G.: Revivals, Awakenings, and Reform, 1978 (Box 150)
    - McLaurin, Melton: Growing Up Southern, 1988 (Box 150)